Jacob William

Software Engineering Intern

Strong skills in design and computer science concepts implementations. Expert in C#, Java, JavaScript and Python and many programming languages frameworks and libraries. This comes with a front-end and back-end experience in real-world projects. A wide experience that ranges from Web applications to Desktop Applications and Mobile Applications.

Experience

2018-11 - Software Engineering Intern

present

Aclara Technologies, LLC

- Developing manufacturing software with real-time analytics, employees
 management, and fetching data from multiple databases and 3rd party APIs
- C# full stack project
- MVC design that includes database models, controllers, and views
- Implemented using complex data structures such as binary search trees to handle the large data fetched from data base and APIs
- Used Microsoft's DevOps to handle projects' tasks and their management

2018-05 -2018-07

Software Engineering Intern

Open Learning Exchange, Inc

- · Worked on Android and Angular projects
- Implemented UI for varies of views and backend logic
- Anticipated in code reviews, pull requests, and bugs on GitHub

Education

2017-03 -2020-04

Southern New Hampshire University, BA in Computer Science

- Taken CS core courses such as: Data Structures and Algorithms course, Advance
 Database courses, Operation Systems course, OOP course, and varies Intro to
 programming courses in different languages.
- GPA 3.6

Projects

Cell Productivity

It features real-time analytics, order management and tracking features. It also has an in-app messaging system for communication between supervisors and assembly-line workers. The backend capabilities comes from different data sets that are fetched from Workday API and the company's Microsoft SQL databases.

Redux Streamer

Social media app set up with very strong authentication system that uses Json web tokens and has an RTMP server to provide live streaming feature to the user. The project uses ReactJS and Redux for the front-end. NodeJS, express server for the backend with Mongo database to hold relevant user info.

Authenticator-ExpressJs

Authentication system for ExpressJS web server. It encrypts plain-text password to hashed password to MongoDB. It also uses PassportJS to implement secure routing API. The purpose of this project is to implement a very secure back end authentication system to prevent data theft.

Barcode Decoder and Encoder

Developed in C# during my internship, this program has the capabilities of generating bar codes in more than 3 formats.

Personal Info

Address

New Hampshire

Phone

603-892-7597

E-mail

amjedcha@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/onlyserenity

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amjedcha

Software

React

Very Advance

NodeJS (ES5, ES6)

Very Advance

LESS, CSS, SCSS (including

@emotions and @styled-components)

Very Advance

C#

Very Advance

Python

Advance

Redux

Semi-Advance

Android in Java

Semi-Advanced

GatsbyJS with GraphQL

● ● ● ● ● Moderate